Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lumba
General Insurance Company Limited's Q4
and FY 2026 earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran,
CFO,
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government,
Mr. Girishesh nayak chief enterprise AI
and technology
Mr. Sep Guradia chief corporate
solutions international and bank
assurance
Mr. Gorav Aurora chief commercial lines
and motor underwriting and claims
and Mr. Girishes Seagal chief health UW
and claims customer service and
operations.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants lines
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchstone phone.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO, ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICS Lombard for quarter 4 and
financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economic and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months coupled
with insights on our company's
performance and our key initiatives.
Following that, our CFO Gopal Walachan
will take you through the company's
financial performance for quarter 4 and
financial year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one. For the first two months, the
Indian economy exhibited continued
momentum of growth from the previous
quarter. Whereas the month of March 2026
has seen has been unprecedented in terms
of the geopolitical challenges. The
ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertaintity
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets. These external
risks could have some spillover effects
on the Indian economy warranting a
measured and watchful approach. That
being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress. This
provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks.
Although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions,
let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by. Retail
sales for private cars, two wheelers and
tractors remained positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
Wahan for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two wheeler
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently for H2 2026 the sales growth
of private car and two wheeler stood at
17.8 and 21.5 as against 4.6 and 3.2
respectively in H1 2026 led by GST
rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter 4 2026 wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheer stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that two
wheeler sales surpassed surpassed their
their pre-COVID peak and were at a
decade high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle
based the data reported by Wahan have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2 2026
versus 14.9%
for H1 2026 and a fullear growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digit for
quarter 4 2026 with broadbased expansion
across segments. Also, vehicle vehicle
financing continued to be an important
contributor to credit growth broadly in
line with the trends observed in retail
automo.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come. Moving to the regulatory update.
You may be aware that IRDA has mandated
insurers to prepare and present their
financial statements in accordance with
the applicable Indas effective 1st April
2026. View we view this as a positive
step as the enhanced disclosure
requirements under India's framework
will meaningfully improve transparency
and align the reporting standards of
Indian insurers with global practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both
India's and Indian gap for 2027 and
2028, it has provided the insurer the
option of seeking forbearance to
transitioning the statutory accounting
to India for the first year. We have
examined the option provided by the
authority and believe it would be
appropriate to seek the forbearance in
order to ensure that the transition is
executed in a calibrated and oper
operationally robust manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiencies, elevating customer service
and also enabling better risk selection
across ecosystem. We believe that over
time it will also enhance transparency,
strengthen trust and create enduring
benefit for the policy holder, insurers
and the broader financial system. Let me
now dwell upon the industry performance
for the year ended March 31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and marel segment, the
gross GDPI growth stood at 13.3% for
2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 12.2% for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes, the business witnessed
elevated level of competitive intensity
and pricing pressure especially in the
fire segment in the second half of the
year leading to muted growth.
The renewal of April 1st, 2026 also are
being reported as a discount to the
previous year reflecting that this trend
is likely to continue for quarter 1 2027
as well. On the positive side, however,
we also would like to mention that the
in the reinsurance renewals for
financial year 2027 have been soft.
The motor segment growth for the
industry stood at 9.2% 2% for financial
year 2026 with the momentum experience
post the GST rationalization the second
half of the year has witnessed improved
growth levels of 10 and a half with the
first half which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 15.4% for 2026 which makes it
the fastest growing segment for last 5
years for from financial year 2022 to
2026.
Within this the group health line of
business grew at 12.8% for 2026 whereas
the retail health g growth stood at
19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2%
in 9 month financial year 2025 to 119.3
in 9 month 2026. The overall combined
ratio for private players remained
relatively flattish for from triple 1.2%
for the period 9 month 2025 to triple
1.5%
for the period 9 month 2026. Due to fing
combined ratio for the motor line of
business continue to remain elevated at
128.1%
for 9 month 2026 with 123.8% for the
period ended 9 month 2025.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in gross
domestic premium income for 2026
compared to the industry growth of 9.2%
for the same period. ICS Lombard
achieved a growth of 18.2% and 15.7% in
quarter 4 and H2 2026 respectively
against an industry growth of 10.9 and
11.2% 2% over the same period.
However, excluding the crop and massel
segment, the company recorded a growth
of 10.2%
and for financial year 2026 while the
industry view at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as again compared to industry
growth of 12.2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, a growth in commercial
lines stood at 6.5% versus industry
growth of 14.2%.
Wills for H2 2026, the growth level
stood at 3.8%
versus industry growth of 9.6%.
Aid amidst competitive pressure, we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious risk selection through our
multi- channelannel distribution. We
continue to maintain leadership position
in liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% for financial year 2026. As again
the industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026, we grew at 2.2%
in the motor segment versus the industry
growth which grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026, we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and a
half% in motor that is 12% with with the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter 4
of financial year 2026 where we achieved
a growth of 15% with while the industry
grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheer and combined and commercial
vehicles stood at 52.8 25.4 4 and 21.8%
respectively for financial year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a 1 byN basis.
For quarter 4 2026, the growth stood at
a robust 38.2%
as again the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail business continue to
demonstrate strong growth of 51.1%
for 2026 significantly outfacing the
industry growth of 19.9% in the same
period.
Consequently, a market share has
improved from 3.3% in financial year
2025 to 4.1% in financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a 2x
growth in the new retail health
indemnity business source compared to
the previous year. Our share of
long-term premium in new business for
retail health stands at 42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025. This
performance has been driven by on
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening a real
health distribution franchise or retail
health uh distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus on
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025 with a
market share being 8.7% for financial
year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various lines of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
year 2026 with the with financial year
2025.
A market share in advanced premium
excluding motor share stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026 up from 9.6%
from financial year 2025.
Our discipline focus on profitable
growth has helped us deliver consistent
outcomes over time with market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters. Our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value over the long term. If
we analyze the 10-year time horizon from
financial year 2020 2016 to 2025, it is
pertinent to note that the company's
average combined ratio stood at 102.9%
reflecting sustained underwriting
discipline across various market
conditions. This would compare favor
favorably with the industry average of
115.3%
over the same period.
Furthermore, our investment performance
has also remained strong. Over the same
10 year uh 10ear horizon, we delivered a
robust average realized yield of 8.7%
supported by prudent assent asset
allocation and effective capital
management over multiple cycles. This in
turn has translated into an healthy
average return on equity of 19.1%
over the 10-year period, which would
compare favorably against the industry
average ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution.
Our one and one team philosophy
continues to foster collaboration and
operational excellence
[clears throat] enabling a unified
approach across the organization.
As a part of this philosophy will now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built in
house. one that materially strengthens
our execution engine. We call it IL1
Force.
IL1 Force is an enterprise productivity
platform which has been in operation for
over a year and is used by over 10,000
sales employees. It is on track to
become the single operating platform for
all our 15,000 employees across the
organization.
IL14 integrates work execution,
performance management, collaboration
and recognition into a single platform,
simplifying operations, reinforcing
execution discipline and driving
accountability with real time enterprise
wide wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle. Its renewal
capability has improved conversion by 5%
while enhanced engagement with while
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably in health indemnity improved
engagement led to a 2x increase in agent
activation and a doubling of new retail
business.
Our picture app, a one-stop solution for
insurance and wellness needs, achieved
21 million downloads as of 31st March
2026, reflecting the growing customer
engagement and digital adoption. The GWP
earned from the ILER app during the
period 2026 was 51 5170 million with the
corresponding premium earning for 2025
which stood at 2237.2
million from a claim intimation
perspective. 67% of the customers now
intimate their health reimbursement
claims through the app while 82% of the
claim intimation of a travel product
trip secure plus went through take care
app will continue to focus on improving
the service experience of our customers
with a single simplified interface for
their insurance requirements we continue
to improve our efficiency level in motor
claims too our preferred partner network
service 75.5% of our nonoem claims for
quarter 4 2026 respectively up from
74.1%
for quarter 4 2025 for 9 months we
recorded an NPS of 69 for motor claims
in the retail segment 98.8% 8% of our
total claims were paid within 30 days
for financial year 2026. For the 9 month
2026 on an account basis, the number
stood at 99.9%
with the corresponding number from the
industry being at 82.1%.
For Ry 1 2026, we recorded an NPS of 73
for health claims demonstrating strong
satisfaction level and reinforcing our
position as a customercentric
organization.
A sahed has further strengthened our on
ground claim supports for our health
customers and our customer coverage
improving by 25% over the previous year.
As a part of their feedback, 95% of a
customer survey rated their experience
as exemplary highlighting the support
provided during claims processing and
assistance with hospital coordination.
This VAMS are focused on best-in-class
service to our customers during the
moment that truly matters.
The one call center initiative continues
to deliver strong momentum in the
company's transition toward the digital
first do-it-yourself service model. In
March 2026, more than five lakh service
engagements, 69% of the total service
engagements were executed digitally. Our
differentiated service initiatives which
we have spoken about in previous
earnings call have resulted in increase
of our call center NPS to 74 in quarter
4 2026 from 60 in quarter 1 2026.
Before I close the current year marks an
important milestone in the journey of IC
Lombard as we enter into our 25th year
of operations. We would like to take
this opportunity to express our
heartfelt gratitude to all our stake
stakeholders who have been truly who has
truly supported us in our journey so far
and we look forward to your continued
trust, encouragement and support in the
years ahead. I will now request Gupal to
take you through the financial numbers
for quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
Thanks Sanjie and uh good evening to
each one of you. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter in the full financial year. We
have uploaded the results presentation
on our website. You can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
with effect from October 1, 2024.
Long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator
IID. Please refer our investor
presentation slide number 16 for the
further details on comparison of
financials on a on an N and one byN
basis. It may be noted that all the
numbers that I've been speaking about
are on a 1 byN basis unless otherwise
mentioned.
On combined ratio, our combined ratio on
an N basis for FI26 was 102.4%.
As against 102.6% in FI25,
our combined ratio on a 1 byN basis for
the current year was 103.4 as against
102.8% in FI25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion the combined ratio for
FI26 stood at 102.1%.
And 103.1%.
On a n basis and 1 by n basis
respectively.
Our combined ratio on a n basis for
quarter 4 was 100.5
as against 102.1 in quarter 4 of fi25.
Our combined ratio on a 1 by n basis for
quarter 4 current year was 101.2. 2 as
against 102.5 in quarter 4 of last year.
On the investments, our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rupes
584.21 billion as at March 31, 2026, up
from rupes 582.96 billion as at December
31, 2025.
Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was at 3.48 times at March
31, 2026
and at 3.6 six times as at December 31,
2025. Investment income was at rupees
47.42 billion in FI26 as against rupees
42.5 billion in FI25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion in Q4 this
year as against rupees 8.77 billion in
Q4 last year. During the quarter under
review, the company has recognized we
have a policy on impairment of uh
investment assets. uh basis that the
company has recognized an impairment on
its equity portfolio investments of
rupees.49
billion in this quarter for FI26 versus
a small ride back that we had of almost
about 3 crores uh that we had in quarter
4 of uh the last financial year driven
by the prevailing market correction. Now
coming to profitability our profit
before tax grew by 10.2% to rupes 36.59
billion in FI26 as against rupes 33.2 21
billion in FI25
excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees.55
billion. The PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees
37.14 billion in FI26.
Our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FI26 as against rupees
6.68 billion in Q4 FI25 on the profit
after tax. Therefore, consequently, on a
1 byN basis, the PAD grew by 10.5% to
rupees 27.72 billion in FI26 as against
rupees 25.08 billion in FI25.
Again, excluding the impact of the wage
code, the PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by
12.2% to rupees 28.14 billion in FI26.
On an N basis, PAT grew by 14.1% to
rupees 27.61 61 billion in FI26 as
against rupees 24.19 billion in FI25
on an end basis excluding the impact of
the wage code the PAT grew by 15.9% to
rupees 28.03 billion in FI26
our PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by 7.3% to
5.47 billion in Q4 this year as against
rupes 5.1 billion in Q4 last year same
numbers on an end basis PAD grew by
15.6% 6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FI26 as against 4.66 billion in Q4 FI25.
Coming to return on average or ROE was
17.8% in FI26 as against 19.1% in FI25
excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion. The roe stood at
18.1%
for FI26.
ROE for quarter 4 current year was at
13.3%.
as again 14.5% in Q4 FI25.
Coming to dividend, the board of
directors of the company has proposed a
final dividend of 7 per share for FI26.
This payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the nuing
general annual general meeting of the
company. The overall dividend for FI26
including the above proposed final
dividend is rupees 13.5 per share. Last
year the overall dividend was rupes 12.5
per share. On solveny, we continue to
exhibit a very healthy solveny ratio of
2.67 times at March 31st, 2026 as
against 2.69 at December 31, 2025, which
continues to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement. The solveny of
course was impacted by roughly about 14
basis points as an outcome of the
marktomarket loss position that we had
on the equity book as at March 31, 2026.
As I conclude, I would like to state
that we are aligned with our resource of
driving profitable growth, consistent
and sustainable value creation for all
our stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are at the
forefront at all times. I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take questions that you may have.
Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchdown
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question Q, you may
press star and two. Participants are
requested to please use handsets while
asking a question. Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now wait for a moment while the
question Q assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Supratim Data from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
Hello. Um, thanks a lot for the
opportunity. My first question is on the
competitive environment in the industry.
Uh, there have been articles recently
indicating that competition in the
commercial lines have been fairly
elevated. You indicated that you know
the motor lines combined ratio remains
elevated. So if you could give us an
idea about you know how competitive
environment in the different segments is
panning out that would be helpful and is
there any improvement due to now uh the
um guidelines kicking in. So that's my
first question. The second question
coming to the loss ratio side uh this
year fourth quarter motor TTP loss ratio
has been significantly lower than what
we have seen in the last uh years um in
uh fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio.
So just wanted to understand you know
what has played out for this uh
significant improvement versus the run
rate that we have seen previously and
why is the crop loss ratio negative if
you could give some color on that.
Lastly on IFRS Popal you know would it
be possible for you to give us some
understanding or clarity regarding you
know how your PAT under IFRS would look
versus the IGAP pat that would be very
helpful. Thank you.
I'll take the second one first.
>> Maybe I can take the second and the
third and then maybe I can ask maybe
Sanjiv can uh respond the first one. Um
I think on the loss ratio of Supra team
I think uh this obviously comes to us
every quarters and I think our response
will still remain the same as in to say
that one you have to keep looking at
motor as a category as compared to one
looking at separately uh motor own
damage and third party. So that's one.
Second, I think we would continue to
again request all of you to keep looking
at numbers more on uh full year basis as
compared to let's say any given quarter
and uh just to kind of uh refresh what
we have been telling the street is I
think the range that we are comfortable
on motor is between 65 to 67 I think
that is the range that we have
maintained and if you have seen for the
full year current year I think we ended
at roughly about 66.3%.
it's well within that range and hence to
that extent I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely. Uh so in that sense there is
nothing that has kind of changed. Uh if
you ask us has has any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change the short
answer is no and we continue to kind of
maintain prudence uh in terms of
maintaining our uh loss reserves. So
hence uh I think we have to keep looking
at numbers more on full year basis as
compared to any given quarters. So
that's one crop. Uh I think again uh
time and again we have kind of talked
about it because generally again just to
kind of refresh most of the businesses
in crop get booked around quarter 2 and
somewhere around quarter 3 and maybe
early quarter 4 because those are
typically the two seasons that largely
get exhibited. In our case, we had
predominantly a large exposure on crop
largely from one state of which a large
part of our premium was something that
had got kind of booked roughly around
quarter two of the year and as we have
said it obviously takes time for the
season to kind of play out in terms of
actual loss experiences and in any in
any quarter when you see that experience
play out then to that extent obviously
and if you recolct even at the time of
booking the policies we obviously follow
a very very conservative approach of
providing for almost 100% % loss ratio
at the time of writing the risk and as
the actual experiences play out
obviously to that extent in case if you
see some kind of a positive change then
to that extent that gets reflected again
in the given uh quarter and hence to
that extent is why possibly you are
seeing that number uh in line with the
loss ratio outcomes for quarter 4. Here
again I would continue to urge that you
should again look at the numbers more on
a full year basis on a full year basis
is pretty much kind of range bound
whether you look at FI25 or whether
whether you look at FI26
um on India's I think uh uh in line with
what we had also kind of put out as a
part of the opening uh transcript um at
this point of time uh given the state at
uh which uh so one if you ask us is the
now now that is now there is a
definitive uh uh state uh in so far as
uh transitioning to ind is concerned. So
hence that's a very very welcome step in
so far as the overall uh industry is
concerned. I think that's what
rightfully so the regulator has done it.
Um in terms of uh uh our own transition
I think we do have uh we have been
working on a plan of action in terms of
getting our uh processes internally uh
up and ready so that we are able to kind
of start reporting uh numbers to all of
you uh uh whenever we are kind of ready
for it. Um at this point of time I think
we will continue to kind of give uh in
line with what we have done even in the
past we have been submitting performer
numbers uh for the last two years. So we
will continue even for 2627 on a
quarterly basis in line with the
requirements we will continue to submit
uh India India's based results to the
regulator and maybe we will come back to
all of you at an appropriate time uh and
then we will possibly start talking
about more specifics in terms of the
impact that it does on both uh the
combined ratios and maybe the return on
equity objectives because those are the
two two things that the market obviously
kind of wants to hear from us. So we
will come back on that uh and maybe on
the first point.
>> So also you know the just to close out
the IFRS part and we've always said in
the past also that uh the year of
adoption there would be a significant
decline in combined ratio. It can be in
the range of 300 basis to you know maybe
400 450 basis point. But look that's
only the accounting part of it. economic
value over a period of time it is
expected to converge and have the same
uh you know uh value creation for the
company as it happens. So so our stand
pretty much remains same and yes from
next quarter one we would end up doing
our submissions on that count. uh with
respect to super on the comp competitive
pressure that is there and we spoke
about that also when we were giving the
overall briefing for the year that has
gone by yes it has intensified on
commercial and business uh at the same
time the the capacity overall on the
reinsurance side was very high available
and we've been able to see to some
extent it getting negated uh will this
continue my my own belief is market
forces will play out but our own
understanding is when we
intensive competition the selection has
to get sharper. Uh because it's will we
compete in the market? Answer is yes. Uh
but uh what we've been able to write and
what we will write we will be creating
differentiation. If you remember last
year even in know over quarters we had
said that there was a marginal loss of
uh market share for us on the fire side
purely was on account of the fact that
uh we will do what is comfortable and
the output is in some ways here to see.
These are all very exposuredriven
products and you have to be cautious of
what you pick and what you don't and
we'll continue to follow that. Uh there
is no overarching worry. We are very
well placed as an institution in terms
of what practices we have to counter any
such measures that come up in the market
and overall insurance general insurance
in particular have seen uh these kind of
conduct at multiple levels and we are
well pleased about it on motor also in a
similar vein uh yes the industry is been
uh stretched at multiple counts the
command ratio which I just spoke about
for the 9 months stays at 128 clearly
not a workable one We continue to pick
and choose uh and deliver uh uh a result
which is differentiated from the market.
It's purely led by on multiple count
distribution and underwriting practices
which differentiates in own damage as
well as third party which briefly you
know uh Gopal spoke about. Thank you.
>> Understood. Perfect. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Pra Jen from Motila Losal.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Uh few questions from
my side. Firstly, if I will, you know,
just wanted to take a view on your
solvency which is like uh very high at
2.7. How do you think that you will uh
whether you because you've been
generating good profits over the past
few years and in fact from FI22 to FI25
and even now the solvency has been
increasing. So how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form or to kind of
because and unless the growth is really
exceptional we I'm sure that we wouldn't
need that kind of excess solveny on the
balance sheet that's question number one
second you know we've been talking about
motor TP price hike and uh you know
we've discussed this in the last call
last few calls as well but given the
trajectory on the motor TP loss ratios
at about 63 63.2 in FI25 and 63.8 this
year for you. Do you think that uh you
know motor TP price hike can uh come in?
Um and my last question is on on the
health insurance front. Uh uh Gopal if
you could split up the loss ratios for
retail retail and group.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So maybe yeah. Uh so uh so
pre uh uh so the first one I think uh um
I think as a company uh what we have
always maintained is uh uh sufficient uh
margins when it comes to solvency
because uh in uh the Indian market is
still on solvency one regulation I think
of course there is a road map to maybe
eventually transition to risk based
capital which again as what as what the
regulator has rightfully done on India
I'm
they would possibly try and do a similar
thing even on transition to risk based
capital as well. So obviously one will
have to wait and see how that plays out
but till that point of time I think the
Indian market continues to be guided by
solvency one uh which uh as I said still
mandates uh capital ask to be maintained
basis the gross exposures that you have
as an entity and hence to that extent
we'll have to be uh mindful of and
prudent uh in terms of the levels of
solveny that we carry as an institution.
Um having said that I think uh to your
point on uh the last few years I think
uh fair observation but if you see I
think last couple of years in specific I
think we have been relatively uh lower
uh when it comes when it comes to growth
but that's something that we have
already seen a clear positive uh
reversal of trends emerging for us and
with the momentum that that we have kind
of seen in all fairness one would
obviously want to kind of make sure that
we are able to kind of get it extended
uh even as we head into FI27 and the
moment you will see as what you have
seen uh let's say even uh in the second
half of this year growth kind of coming
back uh so to that extent obviously one
will uh look at consuming some part of
uh the solveny that we have and three
ours solveny is also guided by obviously
a mix of what is it that we want to
drive in terms of the growth objective
and two at the same time make sure that
we are kind of appropriately kind of
rewarding uh the investors who have kind
of obviously placed faith in us and in
that context I think if you would have
seen historically we do have a board
governed uh dividend distribution policy
in place uh on an average I think what
we have been able to kind of distribute
uh is roughly about uh 25% of our PAT
and this year again as what we had kind
of put out in our opening transcript
roughly about 13 and a half rupees per
share for the full year uh roughly
translates to almost about 25% of our
profit after tax. Uh so hence it's
obviously will be a continued
combination of both uh rewarding the
shareholders appropriately and at the
same time making sure that we are able
to use the capital for uh growth. And
the three the third part as I said we
will obviously kind of keep a watch on
the transition to risk based capital. So
that's one uh to your point on the
breakup for the health loss ratio
numbers I think yeah thankfully this
time the question has come ahead of
time. So so maybe we'll answer it. Uh so
I think uh Q4 of last year this right
now I'll give you the numbers for
quarter 4 employer employee book uh the
last last year Q4 the loss ratio was uh
98% and this year that number is almost
the same at 981%.
On the retail uh indemnity book uh the
loss ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8
and this year quarter 4 the loss ratio
on the indemnity book is at 57.6.
Now the same year numbers on a full year
basis employer employee book for last
year has been at 97.2
and this year full year the employer
employee book loss ratio stands at about
91.9
on the retail indemnity full year last
year was 67.9
this year full year is at about 64.6
six. Uh so just that for now to kind of
sum it again on the indemnity book I
think the range that we have spoken
about is between 65 to 70% and that's
what we have been kind we have been kind
of largely talking through even in the
past several quarters and broadly if you
see the experience that one has seen the
good part is I think one we have been
able to book build a book uh which is
pretty much to our liking and it has
kind of played out both in terms of
growth in market share and also staying
within the loss ratio range. Uh so those
are the responses to the two questions
maybe the motive third party.
>> So uh yes uh I think uh possibly it's
been almost 5 years now since the uh
industry has uh got a hike uh and the
loss ratio at the industry level as far
as motor TP is concerned is at around 85
and thereabouts. uh which is
significantly you know elevated uh where
we are we have been able to uh if you
see and goal briefly spoke about it we
had to also reconfigure our portfolio to
get aligned and drive the efficiency uh
which we've been able to reflect uh it
does at time lead to a loss and whenever
we end up having discussions uh whether
individually or collectively there's so
much of you know questioning as to why
has the market share gone down gone up
that is what it takes to reconsider. Uh
we've also recalibrated our practice in
terms of ground surveillance and doing
what is required uh to avoid fraud which
probably we would easily say is among
the lowest in the industry. There's no
way we can claim to eliminate it. So
there are multiple factors that go about
it. We remain desirous of the fact that
yes the TP hike for the industry is
overdue and uh sooner than later that
should play out. uh but we can only
control what is in in our hand. This one
definitely is not and in line with that
we continue to forge our own uh
understanding and deliberation to
penetrate market at multiple counts and
make it work for us uh as a company and
uh from an industry standpoint sooner
than later we do hope the relief comes
through.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aendis Spark. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity. Uh so so my my my first
question is is that last year we we kind
of lost market share in commercial lines
um and um and given given the market is
soft as you highlighted. uh is it safe
to say that uh we we will claw back kind
of a market share in the software market
or we will remain as cautious as we were
last time and and in and and and in in
in these lines just wanted to understand
given given the soft market growth
outlook uh given given um your second
half growth is 16%age
uh and maybe crop being a new tendering
uh uh tendering uh year uh how do you
see growth of the 16 percentage to
continue for the next here uh and any
any color if you can give on that those
lines will be very useful that that's my
first question maybe maybe I will ask
another one later
>> okay so no shank I think uh last year uh
I'm seeing when you're saying last year
it's the year before the one which you
just given the result which is financial
25 we were we didn't lose market share
we had gained by.1 we had a quarter here
where we missed but overall we had
gained we talking about a market share
which in the range of 13.7 which was
year full this year we have closed by8 7
basis point lower uh and it's driven
through multiple configuration when we
meet up personally for I more than happy
to sit run through that uh these with
that kind of a share that we draw these
fluctuations to ensure that we select
right can happen uh but uh the
commercial practice that we have is very
unique uh in the industry and it's not
driven by what business we are able to
write it's about how we are able to even
manage claims
uh there's a significant contribution on
large corporates to mid and to small.
Honestly speaking from an entity
standpoint we have been we have done a
much more uh uh you know decent job on
the large corporate side and over last
two to three years which we have been
briefing to you it's been a more
distributionled growth and we've been
able to diversify our portf our
portfolio in a in a significant manner.
We do we do believe that uh we are we
have a very significant edge in the
overall practice and we will be able to
uh have a you know a reasonable presence
as far as commercial is concerned. I
don't want to jump the gun to say uh
where the market share will be but we
will be a very relevant player and it's
not uh easy to see us losing foothold on
that on an overarching basis. crop
coming into play. We will uh and yes the
market opens up significantly. We are
still awaiting the details in terms of
on what contours this market will open
as and when those guidelines come in. uh
we will be able to comment as to what it
is but we've always maintained our stand
that crop will be purely on selection
basis of what we feel is appropriate
rather than a targeted segment where
we'll say
no that's not the way we look at it do
we want to participate it's a bold yes
do we want to you know chase it the
answer is no uh we we very well placed
overall uh to and we're excited actually
In terms of the opportunity that will
present itself, uh our current crop
number is what was there year before
last or this year are virtually half and
uh uh there is some play available for
us to make it count in this year.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sorry.
>> No, sorry. You're saying something. Go
ahead. Please go ahead.
>> No, no, no. the the sorry when I meant
uh April last year you lost market share
in commercial lines because you believed
the market was too soft and and if you
are assuming it is too soft again maybe
maybe full year you caught it up but but
but given April is very strong in the
renewal for for uh fire whether whether
whether whether whether it will have any
implication in one Q growth or or April
growth which is which is significantly
very big and and lastly yeah go ahead
lastly on crop crop just just wanted to
add is that uh whether whether you
confined till till last three years to
to one state uh maybe I don't know what
final controls will be but but it is
fair to say that you you will be
expanding beyond a particular state in
in in the current year or not broadly
broadly that's that's way you are
strategically thinking in in those lines
or not is the point I wanted to check
>> yeah yeah so so one state uh worked out
because it was a line of what we wanted
to do it is not a plan that will
continue to be a one state p this we
will go uh wherever it makes uh you know
uh uh commercial sense and we believe
that it is appropriate and crop
obviously can play out the way it is we
are still awaiting structure. So there
is there is we are open to uh whatever
that comes up our way to be very honest
on that point. And on the commercial
part in terms of uh uh what you are
saying look the growth of the industry
itself will get impacted and we are we
are a sub we are an offshoot of that. So
uh uh we can do better we can do worse
depending on how it pans out. uh uh but
overall if you remember in H1 uh we had
a
uh much bigger loss with what happened
in H2. probe uh we've also done what is
required uh so what cannot get you know
what cannot be acquired through uh large
corporates we have played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well entrenched uh so we
should be fine on the commercial part
also overall as an entity
>> understood so so from growth point of
view given sorry to interrupt we request
you to please the growth on commercial
because of fire being there the industry
itself may have challenges is on growth.
Uh let me uh put this very clearly. Uh
but it doesn't mean that uh it put us at
a significant disadvantage as anybody
else. It would be probably single digit.
Sorry just to squeeze in I was asking
that second half our growth was 16%age
though weak in first half. So this 16%
growth run rate uh you expect to
continue largely for FI27.
>> [laughter]
>> There is there is so much happening all
around that uh uh how do we predict that
but yes uh Gopal mentioned that very
briefly we are very confident of moving
into the quarter 1 and quarter two on a
positive note overall as things stand
yes we but how does the industry play
out overall uh we will have to watch at
that uh uh we also presume that the the
the tailwinds which got number of GST
cut which led to a very robust quarter
four uh would continue to play out
definitely we'll be well placed for a
growth. We we are excited with that
opportunity but we'll have to wait in
terms of how the market plays out. Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Yeah. Thanks. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
>> Thanks for the opportunity sir. My
question is on motor. So in motor in H1
we grew less in the market in H2 we grew
faster in the market. So what drove that
and what is the outlook of our growth
with industry growth in FI27 on in the
motor segment.
>> Yeah. Okay. So D I think uh yes S H2 was
better. There was also uh a significant
play that came out on account of new
sales uh for the country doing better
and uh there is no denial in you know
there's nothing which we can say uh that
we tend to do better when new sales are
uh very high and we have seen that new
grew at almost 18.8%
uh for us with this 13.4 on the old
side.
on the outlook of financial year 27 um
we'll have to see we do expect a higher
singledigit growth at the industry level
and if that happens it would be again uh
good for us and other thing which worked
out last year was the growth of two
wheeler by when I was talking I said
that it was at a decade high in terms of
the overall uh growth that happened we
for last three four years we have been
saying that we have not beaten the
pre-COVID number on two billers that
itself is again a big plus uh overall on
the uh motor side. I think the only
thing that I'll just add just to what
Sanji was saying I think one of the
thing initiatives that we have also been
speaking in our earlier calls is our
relentless focus on improving retentions
uh and uh we will be very again happy to
kind of uh indicate that uh for the full
year I think at an aggregate let's say
company level a large part of which will
be predominantly let's say retail
business lines I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points
U so hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FI27. So that will be an
important lever uh that we would
obviously kind of uh uh work on uh
beyond of course the point that Sanjay
made in so far as new vehicle sales is
concerned.
>> Sure. So basically the growth
acceleration that we have seen is the
function of growth new vehicle sales
going up new
competitive intensity reducing and we
gaining market share on a lack to basis.
uh so yeah so new and old and I think it
built sometime in quarter one last year
that we had uh as a company extensively
worked on the retention part a lot of
work was done on multiple counts uh by
us and that's what Gopal is referring to
when he's saying that we had a delta of
higher retention of our customers
>> sure so and that so
should we expect cube H2 trend to play
out next year also that we will grow
faster than the industry
uh are I think I think let me put it
this way we we will we are well placed
overall but uh there are multiple
factors see I mean if there's a there is
a challenge on the energy if the uh if
uh the Indian mentality moves into the
saving part of it rather than spending
the motor sales or auto sales which
probably all of you are well aware of it
actually ends up getting really muted
we'll have to see how that part comes in
uh but we would say that uh the momentum
on quarter 3 to quarter four and so
effectively in quarter 1 should play out
uh I would say yes we are going with a
very positive mindset at this point of
time
>> sure sure uh that's it from myself
>> thanks thanks thanks
>> thank you our next question comes from
the line of Avin Singh with MK Global
please go ahead
>> yeah hi uh thanks for the opportunity uh
good evening a couple of question the
first one subject. I would uh say if you
can uh clarify my understanding this 49
cr kind of a charge that you have taken
for diminish in value of investment uh
provisions in this quarter is it largely
driven by the equity for market fall or
bond or kind of a both so that's one and
second in motor TP of course you have
explained a lot of things uh my question
is that okay we have not seen a sort of
a price hike but what had changed for
you that you have kind of a accelerated
your growth in CV segment. Now typically
from whatever we hear it is a CV by and
large where the price revision is
required and it's not so profitable but
in Q4 uh it seems that you have gone a
lot higher in terms of you know uh that
CV. So what had changed there? What kind
of a strategy is there and for the full
year around 780 crores of motor third
party reserv
I'm seeing correctly? Thanks
>> the last one.
So maybe I can take the last one. Uh so
Ain again again we will keep saying uh
you should keep looking at the loss
ratio range that we have spoken about
for motor as a category which is between
65 to 67. An absolute amount of uh
reserve number that you spoke about
honestly uh in our sense is something
that would not necessarily be a right
metric to kind of track. a better metric
will be to keep looking at the loss
ratio outcome which is the range that we
have kind of spoken about between 65 to
67. Now the good part is I think uh I
think what has worked for us I think is
I think we have seen a clear rebound of
growth and at the same time we have been
able to maintain the loss ratio
expectations that we have set out. uh so
hence to that extent I think uh is where
we have been able to deliver both on
growth as well as in so far as the loss
outcomes and that's something that we
are very very happy with and we are very
very positive uh when we kind of head
into uh FI 27 um and as I said uh in
response to the earlier question is
there any change in the thought process
of any of our reserving philosophies of
reserving processes absolutely no we
continue to maintain prudence we
continue to maintain margins
for any levels of uncertaintity that we
see in any of the book and more so in
the context of motor third party which
has got a long tail uh uh longtail
periods of loss development. So hence to
that extent uh that's in response to the
point on motor third parties. uh to your
first point uh or to to the on the first
question with respect to the 49
crination in the value of investments. I
think this is what I kind of uh
mentioned even as a part of the opening
uh transcript. Uh we have a policy on
impairment of investments uh that we
kind of have in the context of uh equity
investment specifically and consequent
to what we have seen the market
conditions getting exhibited in quarter
four of this year. We have obviously
valuated stocks that we hold and bases
the policy that we have we have done an
impairment of about 49 crores. All of
this 49 crores is in with respect to the
policy on dimination in the value of
equity investments.
>> Yeah. Okay. So now the uh CV growth I
think you're absolutely right. Uh it's
done better but there are you know
multiple moving parts. I don't want to
get into details. We can do it probably
when we meet a vinach uh and talk about
it. uh we've done better but the overall
contribution of CV to the book has still
been range more at 22%.
uh you see multiple you know things and
there's one more aspect that's the cost
of acquisition that comes into play and
if we see moderation we see an
opportunity we are also scanning the
market adding new vectors and something
looks viable we end up doing it we've
also created a significant edge with the
with the market through a fleet
management system which we are working
for last almost uh you know 18 to 24
months and that has also started giving
us some bit of an advantage uh as to
what we can do in commercial vehicles uh
it's it's overarching it's still come
range bound and uh we do believe that
the overall growth in CV market also for
a2 was at a reasonable level which I've
given in the numbers in the details
which also again presented us with an
opportunity to do what is required uh
overall on the practice side if you see
where ICS Lombard is certainly private
car and two-heer is uh our you know our
strength but CV we continue to uh
exhibit uh a lot more intensity but the
outcome used to be moderate uh for us
and for last uh couple of quarters it's
come into play and I sincerely hope that
we'll have a similar trend going forward
next year or this year rather
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you our next question comes from
the line of Nishan Chawat from Kota
please go ahead
Hi. Uh this is slightly open-ended. Uh
uh the regulator is uh you know looking
at uh uh you know newer set of
guidelines on commissions uh you know
probably capping commissions or
deferring them. Uh you know assuming
that you know this kind of leads to some
amount of tightening how do you see this
impact on the industry and for yourself?
uh nish I think we've always maintained
you know uh an an environment with uh
where the regulator enforces it in the
past also we have said that there are
quite a few players who have sought
dispensation or have not followed the
guideline and that does not occur well
any tightening on a uniform basis across
the industry uh would place ICSL umbart
at a significant advantage uh uh because
we've remained within the limits of
expense of management and uh if others
fall in this we can only see uh better
time ahead for us as an industry. the
the only thing that remains is uh it
should be practiced across the industry
at a uniform bas on a uniform basis
>> and it's a welcome sign uh if it comes
out we always also mention the fact that
we believe the expense of management
should be on a single slab basis uh so
that there's clarity of execution and
let the market forces decide as to what
works for each one of them in every
single business line.
So, so what is the latest in terms of uh
you know regulatory engagement on EOM?
Is there any revision expected around
the corner along with this separately?
>> We can we can only say that whatever is
accessed by each one of you is what we
access and the we await for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second guessing but uh any
tightening on account of that would be
welcomed by us because it puts the
industry in uh good path with respect to
policy holder and also for us as an
institution.
>> Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
ladies and gentlemen. We will take that
as a last question for today. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for closing comments.
Over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much for joining in. Uh we
look forward to the new financials with
renewed hope. We've definitely as a team
uh been excited as to how we've been
able to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4
over the rest of it. uh we are positive
in terms of how things can work out for
general insurance industry at large and
with the reforms that the regulator has
put in place. Uh but at the same time we
hope that the the world moves to a in a
in a much more you know peaceful manner
in times to come. So thank you so much
and all the best to each one of you for
joining in. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
Thank you. On behalf of ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.